<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on loikein&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on loikein&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Rosenblatt Transformation and Copulas</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/notes-rosenblatt-copulas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/notes-rosenblatt-copulas/</guid>
      <description>Reference  Repos Links Papers &amp;amp; Books  Example: Economic Order Quantity  Model  Local Sensitivity Analysis  One at a Time Method Scenario Decomposition One Way Sensitivity Function Differentiation-Based Methods Screening: Morris Method  Global Sensitivity Analysis  Non-Parametric Methods Variance-Based Methods Density-Based Methods    Thesis Roadmap
Reference Repos  jonathf/chaospy  ChaosPy documentation  OpenSourceEconomics/econsa  econsa 0.01 documentation  OpenSourceEconomics/tespy covid-19-impact-lab/sid simetenn/uncertainpy  Uncertainpy 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on AppleScript</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/notes-applescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/notes-applescript/</guid>
      <description>References Basics  Hello World Variables Types String Operation List Type Conversion Dictionary If Try File &amp;amp; Path Tell Application  Actually Useful Scripts  Finder Safari    Version of macOS: 10.15.4 (19E266)
Editor: Script Editor.app
References  AppleScript 脚本入门 - 从前端到全栈 - SegmentFault 思否 AppleScript Programming - Wikibooks, open books for an open world AppleScript 入门：探索 macOS 自动化 - 少数派 Introduction to AppleScript Language Guide Mac Automation Scripting Guide   Basics Hello World beep beep 5 display dialog &amp;quot;hello, world&amp;quot; -- &amp;quot;OK&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Cancel&amp;quot; buttons -- In case you missed, this is a comment # this too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Behavioural Public Policy - Problem Set</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/notes-behaviour-public-ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/notes-behaviour-public-ps/</guid>
      <description>Present Bias Optimal Taxation Salience Bias   Present Bias  BPP.PS1.Q1
An individual can choose how to distribute money across two time periods, \(t = 1, 2\) for consumption \(c_1\) and \(c_2\).
The total amount of money available is \(m\).
For every dollar not spent in period 1, the individual receives an interest rate \(r\).
Therefore, the overall budget constraint is given by (1): \[c_1 + c_2\cdot\frac{1}{1+r} = m\] Individuals have \((\beta, \delta)\) preferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Programming Practice: Final Project</title>
      <link>/post/2019/12/effective-programming-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/12/effective-programming-project/</guid>
      <description>Project Description  References Documentation Potentially Useful R Packages  Notes on Minimal Distance Estimation Notes on AGS (2017)  Motivation Model Sample Sensitivity Estimation Example: OLS Generalisation: Classical Minimal Distance (CMD) Instrumental Variable  Application on Gourinchas &amp;amp; Parker (2002)   Project Description Sensitivity Measures for Method of Simulated Moments: diagnostic tools for moments based estimation.
Your task is to implement those tools in Python and to integrate them in estimagic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to JavaScript, Refined</title>
      <link>/post/2019/11/intro-js-refined/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/11/intro-js-refined/</guid>
      <description>References Basics  Constant &amp;amp; Variable String Property Method Built-in Objects  Conditionals  if &amp;amp; else if Truthy and Falsy Short-Circuit Evaluation Ternary Operator switch  Function  Arrow Function Function in Function  Scope Array  Array Methods Nested Array for while do ... while break Iteration  Object  Destructured Assignment Method Built-in Method Nested Object Pass by Reference Loop in Object this get set Factory Function  Class  Static Method Inheritance  Module  Create Module Use Module Named Export &amp;amp; Import (ES6)  Promise  setTimeout then &amp;amp; catch Multiple Promises (Composition) Promise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Behavioural Public Policy</title>
      <link>/post/2019/11/notes-behaviour-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/11/notes-behaviour-public/</guid>
      <description>Behavioural Public Policy Present Bias  Theory: Intertemporal Consumption Work Allocation: (2015 &amp;amp; 2016) Food Choice: Sadoff, Samek, Sprenger (2014 &amp;amp; 2019) Food Stamp: Shapiro (2005) Retirement: Haider &amp;amp; Stephens (2007) Financial Desicion: Chetty et al (2014) Increase Employee Saving: Thaler &amp;amp; Benartzi (2004) Power of Default: Blumenstock, Callen, Ghani (2018)  Behavioral Welfare Analysis  Theory Sufficient Statistic Welfare Analysis Taxation and Consumer Choise: O’Donoghue &amp;amp; Rabin (2006) Taxation &amp;amp; Happiness: Gruber &amp;amp; Mullainathan (2005)  Salience Bias  Salience &amp;amp; Taxation: Chetty, Looney, Kroft (2009) Heterogeneity: Taubinsky &amp;amp; Rees-Jones (2018)  Feedback Interventions  Identifying Salience Bias Welfare Effect of Debiasing Home Energy Reports: (2011 &amp;amp; 2019) Electricity Usage Alert: (2014 &amp;amp; 2020) Shower Feedback: (2018 &amp;amp; 2019)  Habit Formation  Allcott &amp;amp; Kessler(2019) Theories Going to Gym: Charness &amp;amp; Greezy (2009) Commuting: Yang &amp;amp; Lim (2017) Shower Again  Social Preferences &amp;amp; Labour Market  Labour Market Disappointing Pay Rise: Mas (2006) Downward Wage Rigidity: Kaur (2019)  Social Pressure  Models of Social Influence Peer Effects Estimating θ Asking for Giving: Andreoni &amp;amp; Rao (2011) Asking for Voting: (2008 &amp;amp; 2010) Blood Donation: Bruhin et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Effective Programming Practice</title>
      <link>/post/2019/10/notes-effective-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/10/notes-effective-programming/</guid>
      <description>Slides Example Process of A Project  Clone from Remote Create from Local Create from cookiecutter Runtime: Building Runtime: Testing  Shell  Reference Basics Pipeline  TeX Git  Reference Basics Escape Vim Late .gitignore Multiple Branches Tagging Squash Collaboration  (Ana)Conda  Reference Setup for Zsh Create &amp;amp; Delete Environment Kernels Use Sublime with SendCode  Python Waf  Reference Config Build Miscellaneous  Regular Expression   Note: I use macOS Catalina with Zsh (Oh-My-Zsh) and Sublime Text 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometric Theory</title>
      <link>/post/2019/10/notes-econometric-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/10/notes-econometric-theory/</guid>
      <description>Literature Probability Measures  σ- &amp;amp; Borel Field Distribution Function Extension to R^k  Random Variables  Expectation Variance Moments of R^k  Stochastic Convergence  Convergence in Expectations &amp;amp; Almost Sure Convergence Convergence in Probability Convergence in Probability vs. Almost Convergence Convergence in Probability vs. Covergence in p-th Mean Convergence in Distribution Convergence in Distribution vs. Convergence in Probability Central Limit Theorem Stochastic Boundedness (Tightness) Calculus for Convergence in Probability &amp;amp; Tightness  M-Estimators  Linear Regression Model Parametric Model Consistency Uniform Convergence in Probability Asymphotic Normality Variance Matrix  Efficiency Testing  Wald Test Lagrange Multiplier Test Distance Metric Test     Uppercase variables: random variables Lowercase variables: deterministic variables (I missed all the PS classes since PS4)  Literature Asymptotic Theory:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Research: Dynamic Programming</title>
      <link>/post/2019/10/notes-research-dynamic-prog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/10/notes-research-dynamic-prog/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic Programming: Discrete Time  Example: Corn Planting Sequence Problem Functional (Bellman) Equation Bounded and Continuous Rewards Bellman Operator  Stochastic Dynamic Programming  Example: Corn &amp;amp; Rain Random Shocks Example: Kiefer (1989)  Controlled Diffusion and Optimal Stopping  Wiener Process Diffusion Process Ito’s Lemma Example: Geometric Brownian Motion Optimal Control Binary Case: Optimal Stopping Example: Irreversible Investment Under Uncertainty Poisson Process Optimal Exploration in Two-Armed Bandit Problem  Presentation &amp;amp; Term Paper  Besanko Tong Wu 2018 Bonatti Hoerner 2011 Branco Sun Villas-Boas 2012 Che Hoerner 2018 Halac Kartik Liu 2016 Manso 2011 Strulovici 2010  Kremer Mansour Perry 2014 (My Bit)  Real Life Motivation Model Classes of Mechanisms Incentive Compatiblility Threshold Mechanism General Results Stochastic Model Imperfect Infomation Extension    wrt means with respect to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Python 3</title>
      <link>/post/2019/06/notes-python-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/06/notes-python-3/</guid>
      <description>Reference Personal Notes  continue, pass &amp;amp; break if __name__ == &#34;__main__&#34;  Python on DataCamp  Basics Boolean &amp;amp; Comparison Functions Condition &amp;amp; Control Flows Methods Dictionary Tuple Writing Functions Lambda Functions Error Handeling Using Packages  Package: Numpy on DataCamp  Basics Comparison Methods Control Flows  Package: Pandas on DataCamp  Create DataFrame Import &amp;amp; Export DataFrame Access DataFrame DataFrame &amp;amp; Series Filter DataFrame Manipulate DataFrame Control Flows  Package: Matplotlib on DataCamp  Line &amp;amp; Scatter Plot Histogram Plotting Options  Package: Seaborn on DataCamp  Scatter Plot Relational Plot (Facet Panel) Plotting Options Line Plot  Notes from Effective Programming  Simple Examples Containers Converting Between Types Alias List &amp;amp; Loop Dictionary Conditions Docstring Function Module Numpy Test (Manually) Test: pytest    Reference  PEP 8 -- Style Guide for Python Code | Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Behavioural Economics</title>
      <link>/post/2019/04/notes-behavioural/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/04/notes-behavioural/</guid>
      <description>Basic Ideas Standard Neoclassical Model Behavioural = Non-Standard Model  Reference Dependence Behaviour: Endowment Effect Gain–Loss Utility Linear (Piecewise) Loss Aversion Non-Linear Loss Aversion Endogenous Reference Formation  Choice over Lottery Expected Utility Theory Behaviour: Attachment Effect &amp;amp; Comparison Effect Endogenous Reference Formation with Risk Example: Unit Demand with Random Price Behaviour: Allais Paradox Prospect Theory Non-Expected Utility Theory Regret Theory  Time Preference Saving and Consumption Windfall Spending  Time Preference: Sophistication / Naivete Immediate Cost Immediate Rewards Welfare Effect Procrastination in Infinite Time  Time Preference: Market Response Monopolistic Market Time Consistent Consumer Sophisticated Consumer Partially Naive Consumer Competitive Market Shrouded Attributes  Social Preference Distributional (Consequentialist) Model Inequity Aversion Competitive Bilateral Bargaining  Social Preference: Intensional Model Behaviour: Preference for Fairness Model of Fairness Utility and Best Response Equilibrium  Social Preference: Interdependent Preference Model of Spitefulness &amp;amp; Altruism Private Types: Signalling    textbook 1: (DS) The foundations of behavioral economic analysis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Contract &amp; Informational Economics</title>
      <link>/post/2019/04/notes-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/04/notes-contract/</guid>
      <description>Literature Lemon Market: Continuous Quality Perfect Information Unknown Quality Competitive Equilibrium  Lemon Market: Binary Quality Cheap Repair Expensive Repair  Lemon Market: Signalling Timing Strategy Separating Equilibrium Pooling Equilibrium  Adverse Selection: Continuous Types Benchmark Unknown Type Competitive Equilibrium SPNE Constrained (Second-Best) Pareto Optimum  Job Market Signalling Pooling Equilibria Separating Equilibria: Non-Envy Case Separating Equilibria: Envy Case Hybrid (Mixed) Equilibrium Perfect Bayesian Equilibrium (PBE) Equilibrium Refinements  Competitive Insurance Market Identical Consumers Different Types of Consumers  Screening: Non-Linear Pricing Perfect Information: Monopoly Asymmetric Information Continuous Types: Mechanism Approach  Moral Hazard First Best Second Best Risk Neutral Parties &amp;amp; Unlimited Liability Risk Neutral Parties &amp;amp; Limited Liability  Moral Hazard: Constant Absolute Risk Aversion (CARA) Linear Contract Step Contract First Order Approach    Literature  Microeconomic Theory (MWG) A Primer in Game Theory (PGT) The Theory of Industrial Organization (TIO) Contract Theory (CT)   Lemon Market: Continuous Quality  Quality of car: \(s\in [0,\bar{s}]\)  pdf: \(f(s) = α s^{α-1}\) cdf: \(F(s) = s^α\)  Seller’s type: \(θ_1\)  Seller’s preferences: \(\begin{cases}p &amp;amp; \text{sell} \\ θ_1s &amp;amp; \text{not sell} \end{cases}\)  Buyer’s type: \(θ_2\)  Consumption possibilities: 1 or 0 Buyer’s preferences: \(\begin{cases}θ_2s - p &amp;amp; \text{buy}\\ 0 &amp;amp; \text{not buy}\end{cases}\)  Assume \(θ_2 &amp;gt; θ_1\)  Perfect Information  Trade is efficient since \[\begin{aligned}θ_2 &amp;amp;&amp;gt; θ_1 \\ θ_2s &amp;amp;&amp;gt; θ_1s \\ p + (θ_2s - p) &amp;amp;&amp;gt; θ_1s + 0\end{aligned}\] Conditions for \(p\): \(\begin{cases}p \geq θ_1s &amp;amp; \text{(seller)} \\ θ_2s - p \geq 0 &amp;amp; \text{(buyer)}\end{cases}\) hold with \(θ_2s \geq p\geq θ_1s\)   Unknown Quality  Given price \(p\) Seller sells if \[\begin{aligned}θ_1s \leq p \\ s\leq \frac{p}{θ_1} \end{aligned}\] Buyer’s expected quality</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Institutional Economics</title>
      <link>/post/2019/04/notes-institution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/04/notes-institution/</guid>
      <description>Literature Moral Hazard: Hidden Action Timing Benchmark (Unlimited Liability) Limited Liability Agent Offers Contract  Moral Hazard: Hidden Information One-Sided Two-Sided  Adverse Selection One-Sided: Timing First Best Second Best Agent Offers Contract Two-Sided: Timing Benchmark Impossible Case  Hold-Up Problem First Best Observable &amp;amp; Non-Verifiable Information Private Information &amp;amp; Self-Investment Private Information &amp;amp; Cross-Investment  Property Rights Vertical Integration Joint Venture Privatization    Literature Contract Theory Game Theory (multi-stage games) Institutions and Economic Theory (very general and theoretical) Institutional Economics: An Introduction (Groenewegen, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Game Theory</title>
      <link>/post/2019/04/notes-game-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/04/notes-game-theory/</guid>
      <description>Extensive Game (Perfect Information) Strategy Subgame Chance Moves  Bargaining Ultimatum Game Two-Round Ultimatum Game Rubinstein Game Rubinstein Game (Small Time Interval)  Nash Bargaining Problem Nash Axioms Nash Bargaining Solution (NBS) eg) Cournot vs Collusion Kalai-Smorodinsky BS  Coalitional Game General Case (No Transfer) Analogy with Walreasian Equilibrium With Transfer eg) Exchange Economy Non-Emptiness of Core eg) Majority Game Shapley Value  Repeated Game Stage Game (Normal-Form) δ-Discounted Repetition Perfect Folk Theorems Finitely Repeated Game eg) Battle of Sexes (BoS) eg) Prisoner’s Dilemma (PD) eg) Price Wars eg) Time Inconsistency in Public Good    textbook 1: (OR) A Course in Game Theory</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometrics - Exercises</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/notes-stat-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/notes-stat-exercise/</guid>
      <description>Exercise 2.1 (Regression) a b c d e f g h i j  Exercise 2.4 (Regression - True or False?) a b c d e f g h i j k l m n  Exercise 3.2 (Regression - Empirical) a b c d e f g h i  Exercise 3.4 (Regression - Empirical) Exercise 5.1 (Instrumental Variables) a b c d e f g  Exercise 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Microeconomics - First Final</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/notes-micro-final/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/notes-micro-final/</guid>
      <description>Problem 1: Dual Consumer a) b) c)  Problem 2: Law of Supply a) b)  Problem 3: Cournot Competition a) b) c)  Problem 4: Externality a) b) c) d)    Warning: I failed this exam.
Problem 1: Dual Consumer  Joey is a consumer in a world with a single commodity: potato chips.
Assume that potato chips are a divisible good with quantities in gram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometrics - Tests and Statistics</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/notes-stat-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/notes-stat-test/</guid>
      <description>R^2 t-test F-test (Joint Test / Model Test) Wald Test Wald statistic F-statistic  BIC &amp;amp; AIC Nested Model Time Series  J Test (Non-Nested Model) PE Test (Linear vs Log) Chow (Breakpoint) Test Heteroskedasticity Test Goldfeld-Quandt Breusch-Pagan Test  Autocorrelation Test Durbin-Watson Breusch-Godfrey Box-Pierce  Instrumental Variable Test Durbin-Wu-Hausman (Endogeneity) Sargan (Instrument Validity)  DF (Dickey-Fuller) Test Unit Root Deterministic Trend ADF (Augmented Dickey-Fuller) Test Spurious Regression vs Cointegration  Ljung–Box (Portmanteau) Test (Residual Analysis) Hausman Test (FE vs RE) Read Regression Table   Warning: under proofreading</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Mathematics - Past Exams</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/notes-math-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/notes-math-exam/</guid>
      <description>What Relation Space Distance  Set Collection &amp;amp; Operation Proof by Deduction Inclusion of ε  Set Close / Open Closure &amp;amp; Interior &amp;amp; Boundary Convex Maximum &amp;amp; Supremum Dense  Function Image Injection (One-to-one) &amp;amp; Surjection (Onto) Continuity Mean Value Intermediate Value Fix Point Contraction Limit &amp;amp; Differenciation Supremum / Infimum Maximum Maximizer &amp;amp; Argmax Concave &amp;amp; Convex Epigraph  Set × Function Injection &amp;amp; Surjection (revisited) Finite &amp;amp; Countable  Sequence Convergent Limit &amp;amp; Cluster Point (Un-)bounded  Set × Sequence   Words of warning:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Mathematics - Optimization and Dynamics</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/notes-math-optimization-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/notes-math-optimization-dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Optimization Lagrange Method Kuhn-Tucker Method Dual Problem  Dynamics Recursive Analysis Finite Markov Chain Backward Induction    Optimization Lagrange Method  PS11.Q1
Solve \(\max_{(x,y)\in \mathbb{R}^2} x+y\) s.t. \(x^2+y^2=2\)
 Lagrangian: \[\mathcal{L}(x,y,λ) = x+y+λ(x^2+y^2-2)\] FOC \[\begin{aligned} \frac{\partial\mathcal{L}}{\partial x} = 1 + 2λx = 0 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; x &amp;amp;= -\frac{1}{2λ} \\ \frac{\partial\mathcal{L}}{\partial y} = 1 + 2λy = 0 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; y &amp;amp;= -\frac{1}{2λ} \\ x^2+y^2=2 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \frac{1}{4λ^2} &amp;amp;= 1 \implies λ = \pm \frac{1}{2}\end{aligned}\] 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Finance</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/notes-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/notes-finance/</guid>
      <description>General Principles Net Present Value (NPV) Interest Rates Internal Rate of Return (IRR) Tax (Opportunity) Cost of Capital Time Travel for Money Arbitrage Law of One Price Efficient Markets Hypothesis  Cash Flow Stream Perpetuity Annuity  Decision Rules NPV Rule IRR Rule Payback Rule  Bond Bond Price Zero-Coupon Bond Coupon Bond  Stock Dividend-Discount Model Total Payout Model Discounted FCF (Free Cash Flow) Model  CAPM (Capital Asset Pricing Model) CAPM Assumptions Risk and Return Risk Measurement and \(β\) Portfolio Combined Portfolio  Capital Structure Perfect Capital Market Assumptions Finance A Firm Leverage and Risk  Debt and Tax Interest Tax Shield Personal Tax  Financial Distress Trade-Off Theory  Stock Payout Dividend Share Repurchase Tax and Dividend  Options Put-Call Parity Early Exercise (American) Binomial Option Pricing Model    textbook: Corporate Finance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Microeconomics</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/notes-micro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/notes-micro/</guid>
      <description>Preference  Utility Function Continuity Rational Choice Function  Choice  Revealed Preference Relation WARP (Weak Axiom of Revealed Preference) SARP (Strong Axiom of Revealed Preference) Rationalizing Choice Function  Demand (Consumer Preference)  Continuity (revisited) Monotonicity Convexity Special Preferences UMP (Utility Maximization Problem) Indirect Preference &amp;amp; Utility Differentiability Consumer Problem with Differentiable Preference EMP (Expenditure Minimizationg Problem) Dual Consumer Duality Properties Consumer Welfare  Demand (Consumer Choice)  Consumer Problem Demand Function WARP (revisited) Rationalizing Demand Function SARP (revisited) Types of Commodity (Compensated) Law of Demand  Producer  Technology Production Function PMP (Profit Maximization Problem) Law of Supply CMP (Cost Minimization Problem)  Partial Equilibrium  Perfect Competition (Short Run) Perfect Competition (Long Run) Monopoly Cournot (Quantity) Bertrand Duopoly (Price) Total Welfare (Partial)  General Equilibrium (Exchange)  Core Efficiency &amp;amp; Edgeworth Box Competitive Market Equilibrium Total Welfare (Exchange)  General Equilibrium (Production)  Production Equilibrium Total Welfare (Production)  Externality (Perfect Information)  Bilateral Externality Quota Taxation Bargain (Property Right) Multilateral Externality Taxation  Externality (Asymmetric Information)  Bargain Government Intervention Quota Taxation  Public Goods  Private Provision Subsidy    Textbook 1: (RBST) Lecture Notes in Microeconomic Theory (~ #Producer)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Mathematical Proofs</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/notes-math-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/notes-math-proof/</guid>
      <description>Logic Truth table Proof by Deduction  Relation Preorder (Quasi-order) Order Complete Order  Space Distance Cauchy-Schwarz Inequality  Set Collection &amp;amp; Operation Proof by Deduction Inclusion of ε  Set Open / Closed Closure &amp;amp; Interior &amp;amp; Boundary Compact Convex Maximum &amp;amp; Supremum Dense Separated / Connected  Function Image Injection (One-to-one) &amp;amp; Surjection (Onto) Continuity Value Theorems Contraction Limit &amp;amp; Differenciation Supremum / Infimum Maximum Maximizer &amp;amp; Argmax Concave &amp;amp; Convex Epigraph  Set × Function Injection &amp;amp; Surjection (revisited) Finite &amp;amp; Countable  Sequence Convergent Limit &amp;amp; Cluster Point (Un-)bounded  Set × Sequence   textbook: Mathematical Methods and Models for Economists</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometrics - Practice Part</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/notes-stat-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/notes-stat-practice/</guid>
      <description>Compare Models Choose Explanatory Variables Choose Approach: OLS / GLS Weird Model  R Workout Data Generation OLS Regression    Warning: under proofreading
All I wanted was a clear &amp;amp; complete guidance (for upcoming exams).
Textbook: A Guide to Modern Econometrics
Compare Models Choose Explanatory Variables  PS2.Q3
Consider the wage regressions from slide 5 (text P86).
1. Compute F-statistics for comparing the loglinear model with and without squared experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometrics - Theory Part</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/notes-stat-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/notes-stat-theory/</guid>
      <description>OLS Model OLS Method Statistical Model Gauss-Markov Assumptions Linear &amp;amp; Loglinear Elasticity  OLS Estimator Derive b Unbiasedness of b BLUE Unbiasedness of s^2  Normality Assumption Normality of ε Normality of b  Asymptotic Property Converge in Probability &amp;amp; Mean Square LLN (Law of Large Numbers) Consistency of b Consistency of s^2 Asymptotic Nomality  Data Problems Multicollinearity Outliers  Error Problems Heteroskedasticity Autocorrelation (Serial Correlation) White (HC) Standard Error Newey-West (HAC) Standard Error GLS (Generalized Least Squares) Estimator EGLS (Feasible Estimated GLS) Estimator WLS (Weighted LS) Estimator  Regressor Problem: Endogeneity Lagged Dependent Variable Measurement Error Omitted Variable Bias Reverse Causality IV (Instrumental Variable) GIVE (Generalized IV Estimator)  ML (Maximum Likelihood) Model Assumption Property of ^θ Asymptotic Covariance Matrix  Binary Choice Model Regression Model Probit Model Logit Model Likelihood Ratio  Time Series Types of Process Lag Operator Stationary Difference Operator &amp;amp; Integration Deterministic (Linear) Trend OLS Estimation Model Selection Spurious Regression Cointegration  Panel Data Entity Fixed Effect Time Fixed Effect Least Squares Dummy Variable (LSDV) Estimator Within Estimator First Difference Estimator Entity and Time Fixed Effect (2-way) Random Effect Feasible GLS (EGLS) Estimator    Warning: under proofreading</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rmd Template</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/rmd-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/rmd-template/</guid>
      <description>Words of Warning Rmd Reference  Reference Cheatsheet  Inline Code  Executed  Display Code  R Code Chunk R Code (Inline) Code from Other Languages LaTeX Reference  Image Reference Plot   Never write index.md or index.Rmd. Always use _index.Rmd.
(Per Issue #84)  Words of Warning I use Typora &amp;amp; Sublime Text to write my posts.
Typora’s WYSIWYG mode usually processes .Rmd file correctly, but gets lost in a file as complicated as this one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>