<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on loikein</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on loikein</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Introduction to JavaScript</title>
      <link>/2019/02/notes-intro-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/notes-intro-js/</guid>
      <description>Basics Constant Variable Assignment Operator Increment Operator String + Varible Property Method  Built-in Object Math Number  Conditional Statement if Truthy and Falsy Short-Circuit Evaluation Ternary Operator else if switch  Function Default Argument Arrow Function Function in Function  Scope Scope Pollution Good Scoping  Array let &amp;amp; const Array Method Nested Array  Loop for while do ... while break Iteration  Object Destructured Assignment Method Built-in Method Nested Object Pass by Reference Loop in Object this get set Factory Function  Class Static Method Inheritance  Module Create Module Use Module Named Export &amp;amp; Import (ES6)  Promise setTimeout then &amp;amp; catch Multiple Promises (Composition) Promise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometrics - Tests and Statistics</title>
      <link>/2019/02/notes-stat1-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/notes-stat1-test/</guid>
      <description>\(R^2\) t-test F-test (Joint Test) Wald Test Wald statistic F-statistic  BIC &amp;amp; AIC Nested Model Time Series  J Test (Non-Nested Model) PE Test (Linear vs Log) Chow (Breakpoint) Test Durbin-Watson Test (Autocorrelation) Goldfeld-Quandt Test (Heteroskedasticity) Breusch-Pagan (LM) Test (Heteroskedasticity) Breusch-Godfrey Test (Autocorrelation) Box-Pierce Test (Autocorrelation) Sargan Test (GIVE Overidentification) Durbin-Wu-Hausman Test (Endogeneity) DF (Dickey-Fuller) Test Unit Root Deterministic Trend ADF (Augmented Dickey-Fuller) Test Spurious Regression vs Cointegration  Ljung–Box (Portmanteau) Test (Residual Analysis) Hausman Test (FE vs RE) Read Regression Table   Warning: under proofreading</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Mathematics - Past Exams</title>
      <link>/2019/01/notes-math-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/notes-math-exam/</guid>
      <description>Relation Space Distance  Set Collection &amp;amp; Operation Proof by Deduction Inclusion of \(B_ε\)  Set Close / Open Closure &amp;amp; Interior &amp;amp; Boundary Convex Maximum &amp;amp; Supremum Dense  Function Increasing / Decreasing Continuous Value Theorems Contraction Limit &amp;amp; Differenciation Supremum / Infimum Maximum Maximizer &amp;amp; Argmax Concave &amp;amp; Convex Epigraph  Set \(\times\) Function Injection &amp;amp; Surjection (revisited) Finite &amp;amp; Countable  Sequence (Un-)bounded Convergent Limit &amp;amp; Cluster Point  Set \(\times\) Sequence   Wrote by a MSc student dying of end-of-term reviews (a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Mathematics - Optimization</title>
      <link>/2019/01/notes-math-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/notes-math-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Lagrange Method Kuhn-Tucker Method Dual Problem   Lagrange Method  PS11.Q1
Solve \(\max_{(x,y)\in \mathbb{R}^2} x+y\) s.t. \(x^2+y^2=2\)
 Lagrangian: \[\mathcal{L}(x,y,λ) = x+y+λ(x^2+y^2-2)\] FOC \[\begin{aligned} \frac{\partial\mathcal{L}}{\partial x} = 1 + 2λx = 0 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; x &amp;amp;= -\frac{1}{2λ} \\ \frac{\partial\mathcal{L}}{\partial y} = 1 + 2λy = 0 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; y &amp;amp;= -\frac{1}{2λ} \\ x^2+y^2=2 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \frac{1}{4λ^2} &amp;amp;= 1 \implies λ = \pm \frac{1}{2}\end{aligned}\] 1. When \(λ = \frac{1}{2}\)
\[\begin{aligned} x &amp;amp;= -1 \\ y &amp;amp;= -1 \\ x+y &amp;amp;= -2\end{aligned}\] 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Finance</title>
      <link>/2019/01/notes-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/notes-finance/</guid>
      <description>General Principles Net Present Value (NPV) Interest Rates Internal Rate of Return (IRR) Tax (Opportunity) Cost of Capital Time Travel for Money Arbitrage Law of One Price  Cash Flow Stream Perpetuity Annuity  Decision Rules NPV Rule IRR Rule Payback Rule  Bond Bond Price Zero-Coupon Bond Coupon Bond  Stock Dividend-Discount Model Total Payout Model Discounted FCF (Free Cash Flow) Model  CAPM (Capital Asset Pricing Model) CAPM Assumptions Risk and Return Risk Measurement and \(β\) Portfolio Combined Portfolio  Capital Structure Perfect Capital Market Assumptions Finance A Firm Leverage and Risk  Debt and Tax Interest Tax Shield Personal Tax  Financial Distress Trade-Off Theory  Stock Payout Dividend Share Repurchase Tax and Dividend  Options Put-Call Parity Early Exercise (American) Binomial Option Pricing Model    textbook: Corporate Finance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Microeconomics</title>
      <link>/2019/01/notes-micro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/notes-micro/</guid>
      <description>Preference Utility Function Continuous Preference  Choice Revealed Preference Relation WARP (Weak Axiom of Revealed Preference) SARP (Strong Axiom of Revealed Preference)  Preference × Choice Rational Choice Function Rationalization  Consumer Preference Convex Homothetic Preference Quasi-Linear Preference Differentiable Preference  Demand (Consumer Choice) Demand Function WARP (revisited) (Compensated) Law of Demand  Consumer Preference × Demand Demand with Differentiable Preference Rational Demand Function Indirect Preference (Over Budget Sets)  Dual Consumer Duality Properties  Producer Technology Production Function Supply Law of Supply  Partial Equilibrium Perfect Competition (Short Run) Perfect Competition (Long Run) Monopoly Cournot (Quantity) Bertrand Duopoly (Price)  General Equilibrium (Exchange) Core Competitive Market  General Equilibrium (Production) Welfare With Exchange With Production  Externality   Textbook 1: Lecture Notes in Microeconomic Theory (~ #Producer)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Mathematical Proofs</title>
      <link>/2019/01/notes-math-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/notes-math-proof/</guid>
      <description>Logic Truth table Proof by Deduction  Relation Preorder (Quasi-order) Order Complete Order  Space Distance Cauchy-Schwarz Inequality  Set Collection &amp;amp; Operation Proof by Deduction Inclusion of ε  Set Open / Closed Closure &amp;amp; Interior &amp;amp; Boundary Compact Convex Maximum &amp;amp; Supremum Dense Separated / Connected  Function Image Injection (One-to-one) &amp;amp; Surjection (Onto) Continuity Value Theorems Contraction Limit &amp;amp; Differenciation Supremum / Infimum Maximum Maximizer &amp;amp; Argmax Concave &amp;amp; Convex Epigraph  Set × Function Injection &amp;amp; Surjection (revisited) Finite &amp;amp; Countable  Sequence Convergent Limit &amp;amp; Cluster Point (Un-)bounded  Set × Sequence   Wrote by a MSc student dying of end-of-term reviews (a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometrics - Practice Part</title>
      <link>/2019/01/notes-stat1-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/notes-stat1-practice/</guid>
      <description>Compare Models Choose Explanatory Variables Choose Approach: OLS / GLS Weird Model  R Workout Data Generation OLS Regression    Warning: under proofreading
All I wanted was a clear &amp;amp; complete guidance (for upcoming exams).
Textbook: A Guide to Modern Econometrics
Compare Models Choose Explanatory Variables  PS2.Q3
Consider the wage regressions from slide 5 (text P86).
1. Compute F-statistics for comparing the loglinear model with and without squared experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometrics - Theory Part</title>
      <link>/2019/01/notes-stat1-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/notes-stat1-theory/</guid>
      <description>Gauss-Markov Assumptions OLS Error Normality of \(ε\) Unbiasedness of \(s^2\) Consistency of \(s^2\)  OLS Estimator Derive OLS Normality of \(b\) Unbiasedness of \(b\) Consistent of \(b\) (Asymptotic) Efficienty BLUE (Best Linear Unbiased Estimator) CAN (Consistent and Asymptotically Normal)  OLS Model Converge in Probability &amp;amp; Mean Square LLN (Law of Large Numbers) Loglinear Model Elasticity  GLS (Generalized Least Squares) Estimator GLS Transformation EGLS (Feasible Estimated GLS) Estimator  IV (Instrument Variable) Derive IV IV Estimator \(\hat{β}_{IV}\) GIVE (Generalized IV Estimator)  Heteroskedasticity &amp;amp; Autocorrelation White (Hetero-Consistent) Standard Error HAC (Robust) Standard Error  ML (Maximum Likelihood) Model Assumption Property of \(\hat{θ}\) Asymptotic Covariance Matrix \(V\)  Binary Choice Model Regression Model Probit Model Logit Model Likelihood Ratio  Time Series Types of Process Lag Operator Stationary Difference Operator &amp;amp; Integration Deterministic (Linear) Trend OLS Estimation Model Selection  Panel Data Entity Fixed Effect Time Fixed Effect Least Squares Dummy Variable (LSDV) Estimator Within Estimator First Difference Estimator Entity and Time Fixed Effect (2-way) Random Effect Feasible GLS (EGLS) Estimator    Warning: under proofreading</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Introduction to C Language</title>
      <link>/2018/05/notes-intro-c-rmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/notes-intro-c-rmd/</guid>
      <description>0419 1.2 プリント 2.a 変数 2.b 変数の型 2.c 演算子 2.d プリント2 3.a プリントと変数 3.b プリント：出力指定 3.3 円の面積 3.4 演算子2 4.a 読み込み 4.2 読み込みと円の面積 4.3 読み込みと三角形の面積 5.a 型の変換 5.b 型の変換2 5.3 型の変換と平均値 6.2 数学関数と円の面積  0426 7.c if else：大きい方を出力 7.2 if else：等さの判断 7.3 if else：偶数か奇数かの判断 7.4 if else：等さの判断2 8.a if else：入れ子 8.b ３つの整数の最大値判断 8.4 ３つの整数の最小値判断 8.5 BMIの計算・判定 8.6 閏年 8.7 自販機 9.b switch 10.a ループ：for 10.b ループ：合計の計算 10.c ループ：合計の計算2 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rmd Template</title>
      <link>/2018/01/rmd-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/rmd-template/</guid>
      <description>Words of Warning Rmd Reference Reference Cheatsheet  Inline Code Executed  Display Code R Code Chunk R Code (Inline) Code from Other Languages LaTeX Reference  Image Reference Plot   Words of Warning I use Typora to write my posts. It usually processes .Rmd file correctly, but it gets lost in a file as complicated as this one.
Always check twice and preview the .html page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>