<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on loikein&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on loikein&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to JavaScript, Refined</title>
      <link>/post/2019/11/intro-js-refined/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/11/intro-js-refined/</guid>
      <description>References Basics  Constant &amp;amp; Variable String Property Method Built-in Objects  Conditionals  if &amp;amp; else if Truthy and Falsy Short-Circuit Evaluation Ternary Operator switch  Function  Arrow Function Function in Function  Scope Array  Array Methods Nested Array for while do ... while break Iteration  Object  Destructured Assignment Method Built-in Method Nested Object Pass by Reference Loop in Object this get set Factory Function  Class  Static Method Inheritance  Module  Create Module Use Module Named Export &amp;amp; Import (ES6)  Promise  setTimeout then &amp;amp; catch Multiple Promises (Composition) Promise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Effective Programming Practice</title>
      <link>/post/2019/10/notes-effective-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/10/notes-effective-programming/</guid>
      <description>Slides Example Process of A Project Shell  Reference Basics Pipeline  TeX Git  Reference Basics Escape Vim Late .gitignore Multiple Branches Tagging Collaboration  (Ana)Conda  Reference Setup for Zsh Create &amp;amp; Delete Environment Kernels Use Sublime with SendCode  Python Waf  Reference Config Build Miscellaneous    Note: I use macOS Catalina with Zsh (Oh-My-Zsh) and Sublime Text 3.
Please use Google to tailor your own version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Python 3</title>
      <link>/post/2019/06/notes-python-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/06/notes-python-3/</guid>
      <description>Reference Python on DataCamp  Basics Boolean &amp;amp; Comparison Functions Condition &amp;amp; Control Flows Methods Dictionary Packages  Package: Numpy on DataCamp  Basics Comparison Methods Control Flows  Package: Pandas on DataCamp  Create DataFrame Import &amp;amp; Export DataFrame Access DataFrame DataFrame &amp;amp; Series Filter DataFrame Manipulate DataFrame Control Flows  Package: Matplotlib on DataCamp  Line &amp;amp; Scatter Plot Histogram Plotting Options  Notes from Effective Programming  Simple Examples Containers Converting Between Types Alias List &amp;amp; Loop Dictionary Conditions Function Module  Package: Pandas   Reference  PEP 8 -- Style Guide for Python Code | Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rmd Template</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/rmd-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/rmd-template/</guid>
      <description>Words of Warning Rmd Reference Reference Cheatsheet  Inline Code Executed  Display Code R Code Chunk R Code (Inline) Code from Other Languages LaTeX Reference  Image Reference Plot   Words of Warning I use Typora &amp;amp; Sublime Text to write my posts.
Typora’s WYSIWYG mode usually processes .Rmd file correctly, but gets lost in a file as complicated as this one.
When writing long posts in Sublime, minimap &amp;amp; Ouline plugin can be quite handy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>