<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stat on loikein&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>/tags/stat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in stat on loikein&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/stat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometric Theory</title>
      <link>/post/2019/10/notes-econometric-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/10/notes-econometric-theory/</guid>
      <description>Literature Probability Measures  σ- &amp;amp; Borel Field Distribution Function Extension to R^k  Random Variables  Expectation Variance Moments of R^k  Stochastic Convergence  Convergence in Expectations &amp;amp; Almost Sure Convergence Convergence in Probability Convergence in Probability vs. Almost Convergence Convergence in Probability vs. Covergence in p-th Mean Convergence in Distribution Convergence in Distribution vs. Convergence in Probability Central Limit Theorem Stochastic Boundedness (Tightness) Calculus for Convergence in Probability &amp;amp; Tightness  M-Estimators  Linear Regression Model Parametric Model Consistency Uniform Convergence in Probability Asymphotic Normality Variance Matrix  Efficiency Testing  Wald Test Lagrange Multiplier Test Distance Metric Test     Uppercase variables: random variables Lowercase variables: deterministic variables (I missed all the PS classes since PS4)  Literature Asymptotic Theory:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometrics - Exercises</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/notes-stat-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/notes-stat-exercise/</guid>
      <description>Exercise 2.1 (Regression) a b c d e f g h i j  Exercise 2.4 (Regression - True or False?) a b c d e f g h i j k l m n  Exercise 3.2 (Regression - Empirical) a b c d e f g h i  Exercise 3.4 (Regression - Empirical) Exercise 5.1 (Instrumental Variables) a b c d e f g  Exercise 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometrics - Tests and Statistics</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/notes-stat-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/notes-stat-test/</guid>
      <description>R^2 t-test F-test (Joint Test / Model Test) Wald Test Wald statistic F-statistic  BIC &amp;amp; AIC Nested Model Time Series  J Test (Non-Nested Model) PE Test (Linear vs Log) Chow (Breakpoint) Test Heteroskedasticity Test Goldfeld-Quandt Breusch-Pagan Test  Autocorrelation Test Durbin-Watson Breusch-Godfrey Box-Pierce  Instrumental Variable Test Durbin-Wu-Hausman (Endogeneity) Sargan (Instrument Validity)  DF (Dickey-Fuller) Test Unit Root Deterministic Trend ADF (Augmented Dickey-Fuller) Test Spurious Regression vs Cointegration  Ljung–Box (Portmanteau) Test (Residual Analysis) Hausman Test (FE vs RE) Read Regression Table   Warning: under proofreading</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometrics - Practice Part</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/notes-stat-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/notes-stat-practice/</guid>
      <description>Compare Models Choose Explanatory Variables Choose Approach: OLS / GLS Weird Model  R Workout Data Generation OLS Regression    Warning: under proofreading
All I wanted was a clear &amp;amp; complete guidance (for upcoming exams).
Textbook: A Guide to Modern Econometrics
Compare Models Choose Explanatory Variables  PS2.Q3
Consider the wage regressions from slide 5 (text P86).
1. Compute F-statistics for comparing the loglinear model with and without squared experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Econometrics - Theory Part</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/notes-stat-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/notes-stat-theory/</guid>
      <description>OLS Model OLS Method Statistical Model Gauss-Markov Assumptions Linear &amp;amp; Loglinear Elasticity  OLS Estimator Derive b Unbiasedness of b BLUE Unbiasedness of s^2  Normality Assumption Normality of ε Normality of b  Asymptotic Property Converge in Probability &amp;amp; Mean Square LLN (Law of Large Numbers) Consistency of b Consistency of s^2 Asymptotic Nomality  Data Problems Multicollinearity Outliers  Error Problems Heteroskedasticity Autocorrelation (Serial Correlation) White (HC) Standard Error Newey-West (HAC) Standard Error GLS (Generalized Least Squares) Estimator EGLS (Feasible Estimated GLS) Estimator WLS (Weighted LS) Estimator  Regressor Problem: Endogeneity Lagged Dependent Variable Measurement Error Omitted Variable Bias Reverse Causality IV (Instrumental Variable) GIVE (Generalized IV Estimator)  ML (Maximum Likelihood) Model Assumption Property of ^θ Asymptotic Covariance Matrix  Binary Choice Model Regression Model Probit Model Logit Model Likelihood Ratio  Time Series Types of Process Lag Operator Stationary Difference Operator &amp;amp; Integration Deterministic (Linear) Trend OLS Estimation Model Selection Spurious Regression Cointegration  Panel Data Entity Fixed Effect Time Fixed Effect Least Squares Dummy Variable (LSDV) Estimator Within Estimator First Difference Estimator Entity and Time Fixed Effect (2-way) Random Effect Feasible GLS (EGLS) Estimator    Warning: under proofreading</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>