<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on loikein&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on loikein&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Programming Practice: Final Project</title>
      <link>/post/2019/12/effective-programming-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/12/effective-programming-project/</guid>
      <description>Project Description  References Documentation Potentially Useful R Packages  Notes on Minimal Distance Estimation Notes on AGS (2017)  Multivation Model Sample Sensitivity Estimation Example: OLS Generalisation: Classical Minimal Distance (CMD) Instrumental Variable  Application on Gourinchas &amp;amp; Parker (2002)   Project Description Sensitivity Measures for Method of Simulated Moments: diagnostic tools for moments based estimation.
Your task is to implement those tools in Python and to integrate them in estimagic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Effective Programming Practice</title>
      <link>/post/2019/10/notes-effective-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/10/notes-effective-programming/</guid>
      <description>Slides Example Process of A Project  Clone from Remote Create from Local Create from cookiecutter Runtime: Building Runtime: Testing  Shell  Reference Basics Pipeline  TeX Git  Reference Basics Escape Vim Late .gitignore Multiple Branches Tagging Collaboration  (Ana)Conda  Reference Setup for Zsh Create &amp;amp; Delete Environment Kernels Use Sublime with SendCode  Python Waf  Reference Config Build Miscellaneous  Regular Expression   Note: I use macOS Catalina with Zsh (Oh-My-Zsh) and Sublime Text 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Python 3</title>
      <link>/post/2019/06/notes-python-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/06/notes-python-3/</guid>
      <description>Reference Personal Notes  continue, pass &amp;amp; break if __name__ == &#34;__main__&#34;  Python on DataCamp  Basics Boolean &amp;amp; Comparison Functions Condition &amp;amp; Control Flows Methods Dictionary Tuple Writing Functions Lambda Functions Error Handeling Using Packages  Package: Numpy on DataCamp  Basics Comparison Methods Control Flows  Package: Pandas on DataCamp  Create DataFrame Import &amp;amp; Export DataFrame Access DataFrame DataFrame &amp;amp; Series Filter DataFrame Manipulate DataFrame Control Flows  Package: Matplotlib on DataCamp  Line &amp;amp; Scatter Plot Histogram Plotting Options  Package: Seaborn on DataCamp  Scatter Plot Relational Plot (Facet Panel) Plotting Options Line Plot  Notes from Effective Programming  Simple Examples Containers Converting Between Types Alias List &amp;amp; Loop Dictionary Conditions Function Module Numpy Test (Manually) Test: pytest    Reference  PEP 8 -- Style Guide for Python Code | Python.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>